Freddie (Fred) Hubert

4618 Smokey Wreath Way, Ellicott City, MD | (443) 546-0314 | f.hubert.712@gmail.com | linkedin.com/in/freddie-hubert

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

20 + years of experience in software development and testing, building enterprise level Java applications from the ground up. Adhere to established testing and analysis standards, including software development life cycle (SDLC), Agile, documentation, peer reviews, coding standards and best practices. A proven record of success developing and updating information systems that improve overall business performance and efficiency. Design applications that deliver value and enhance the user experience. Managed teams and projects to ensure work was completed on schedule, within budget and in accordance with scope. Work with stakeholders to perform analysis, testing and reporting. Excellent interpersonal and communication skills with the ability to interact effectively with teams across the organization, and clients with diverse backgrounds.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Java | Spring Boot | Angular | Python | Microsoft SQL Server | RESTful Services | JavaScript Object Notation | XML | SOAP | Rabbit MQ | Splunk | Voltage | Maven | Azure Service Bus | Perforce | Eclipse IDE | ASP.NET | PostgreSQL | VS Code | IntelliJ

AREAS OF EXPERTISE

Microservices | Java Message Service | Debugging | Code Coverage | Application Programming Interface | Database Design End-to-End Testing | Azure DevOps Scrum | Splunk | Dynatrace | Grafana | Software Architect | Agile Software Development | Continuous Improvement | Team Development & Leadership | Client/Customer Service | End User Support | Customer Relationship Management | Data Analysis | Azure DevOps | Software Design | Problem Solving and Debugging | Code Coverage | Software Development Life Cycle | Web Services

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

GEICO INSURANCE | Chevy Chase, MD | Full-time Senior Engineer | 12/2020 - 12/2023

11/1990 - 12/2023

- Developed and maintained infrastructure models using Splunk ITSI to monitor cloud technologies to detect
 application errors. Implemented automated process to move application to standby region, which minimized outage
 time and sustained business continuity. The automated process reduced the switchover time by 60%.
- Designed dashboards used by application teams and technology engineers to monitor infrastructure and alert teams of potential system outages before they have a negative business impact.
- Developed Python/Flask application to automate the generation of SRE (SLO/SLI) Dynatrace dashboard.
- Developed Splunk dashboards using Machine Learning (ML) to detect and predict errors before being reported. This helped reduce production outages and improved customer satisfaction.
- Created new testing initiatives for Splunk ITSI modeling which resulted in standardized testing for 100% of the models.

Senior Java Software Developer – Backend | 7/1996 - 12/2020

- Developed and maintained Java applications, including text messaging, email, and push notifications to communicate with current and potential policyholders. This reduced the number of phone calls coming to the sales counselors and virtually eliminated call hold time.
- Implemented Java system to validate and cleanse bad email addresses being entered into the system, and to manage blocked/unsubscribed emails. This reduced the number of bounced emails by an average of 35%.
- Created a Java system that allowed our text messaging customers to stay in the text messaging channel when communicating with service counselors. Prior to this, the counselor would call or send an email to the policyholder. This improved customer response time and increased satisfaction.
- Re-designed RESTful web service that was Voltage encryption/decryption security. This system replaces a legacy (SOAP) system that did not meet new coding and security standards and was difficult to maintain. Project implemented 2 months ahead of schedule.
- Created a Java application used in a Marketing Promotion, soliciting customers to vote on their favorite commercial via a web portal for a chance to appear in a future commercial. The application was delivered one month ahead of schedule despite having to resolve multiple issues with the vendor.

- Designed and coded a new Java in-app and message center system. This required keeping the existing system
 functioning while simultaneously converting 9 million enrollments on the day we switched to the new vendor. It was
 completed without any issues.
- Developed reusable code libraries that isolated the API calls to vendors. When a vendor changed, the core application was not affected, which allowed for more efficient development and reduced dependency on the outside vendor.

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Science (BS) in Computer Science

DeVry University, Atlanta, Georgia

CERTIFICATIONS and CERTIFICATES AZ-900 Azure Fundamentals Certification

Microsoft

Learning Spring with Spring Boot

LinkedIn Learning

Spring Boot 2.0 Essential Training

LinkedIn Learning

Microservices Foundations

LinkedIn Learning

DevOps Foundations

LinkedIn Learning

Azure DevOps: Continuous Delivery with YAML

LinkedIn Learning

Azure Functions for Developers

LinkedIn Learning

Building a Web Application on Microsoft Azure

LinkedIn Learning

Grafana

Udemy

Learning Docker

LinkedIn Learning

Azure for Architects: Design a Compute Strategy

LinkedIn Learning